export const quizData = {
    title: 'General Knowledge Quiz',
    description: 'Test your knowledge with these general knowledge questions!',
    questions: [
      { 
      question: '1.  Doubling the volume of an ideal gas at constant temperature will ',
      options: [' Double the pressure ', 'Half the temperature ', 'Half the pressure', 'Increase the pressure by halve '],
      answer: 'Half the pressure'
      },
      { 
      question: ' 2.  According to the kinetic theory, molecules of different gasses at the same temperature always have the same   ',
      options: [' Average density ', ' Volume', 'Pressure ', 'Average kinetic energy'],
      answer: 'Average kinetic energy'
      },
      { 
      question: '3. As solid elements melts, the atom becomes __ and they have ___ attraction for one another  ',
      options: [' Closer together, more ', 'More separated, more  ', 'Larger greater ', 'More separated, less'],
      answer: 'More separated, less'
      },
      { 
      question: '4.  The tendency of an electrode to release to or attract electron from the surrounding electrolyte solution at 298K temperature 1atm pressure and 1ml/dm3 conc. Is known as ',
      options: [' Electrolytic potential  ', ' Electrode potential ', 'Standard electrolytic potential  ', 'Standard electrode potential'],
      answer: 'Standard electrode potential'
      },
      { 
      question: '5. The molar solubility of lead (II) Log in Sign up chloride is 1.5 � 10^-2 mol/dm 3. What is the solubility product of the salt? ',
      options: ['3.0 x 10^-2 ', '30.0 x 10^-2 ', '4.0 x 10^-2 ', '1.5 x 10^-2'],
      answer: '1.5 x 10^-2'
      },
      { 
      question: '6. When dH is negative, the reaction is said to be ',
      options: [' Endothermic ', 'Exothermic', ' Reversible', ' Catalytic'],
      answer: 'Exothermic'
      },
      { 
      question: '7. Which of the following statement is true of an acid conjugate base?',
      options: [' Neutralized one another  ', ' Differ only by proton  ', ' Form salt and water only ', 'Carry opposite charges'],
      answer: 'Carry opposite charges'
      },
      { 
      question: '8. The pK of the base XOH, YOH and ZOH are 2.70, 8.60 and 4.50 respectively. Arrange them in order of increasing strength ',
      options: [' XOH, YOH, ZOH', ' YOH, XOH, ZOH ', 'XOH, ZOH, YOH ', 'YOH, ZOH, XOH' ],
      answer: 'YOH, ZOH, XOH'
      },
      { 
      question: '9. The property of substance that relate to its ability to form new substances are labeled  ',
      options: ['Physical ', 'Chemical', ' Extensive', 'Intensive '],
      answer: 'Chemical'
      },
      { 
      question: '10. An example of physical change produce by addition of energy is ',
      options: ['Lighting of a match ', 'Burning ', 'Melting of ice', ' Condensation of steam'],
      answer: 'Melting of ice'
      },
      { 
      question: '11. Which of the following is true? If two gases under the same conditions have the same number of molecule then they must (i) have the same number of molecule (ii) occupy the same volume (iii) different number of molecules (iv) occupy different volume ',
      options: ['I only ', 'I and ii', 'ii and iii ', 'iii and iv '],
      answer: 'I and ii'
      },
      { 
      question: '12. In thermo chemistry, the reference standard state for gases, liquid and solid is said to be at ',
      options: ['25C/1atm', ' 0C /10 atm', ' 1C/60atm', '1273K/10atm '],
      answer: '25C/1atm'
      },
      { 
      question: '13. The thermodynamic state Log in Sign up function that is a measure of disorderliness is  ',
      options: ['Lavoiser', 'Dalton ', 'Proust ', ' Boyta'],
      answer: 'Lavoiser'
      },
      { 
      question: '14. The salt resulting from the reaction of both strong acid and base is likely to be a/an  ',
      options: ['Acid Salt ', ' Basic Salt', 'Neutral', 'No reaction '],
      answer: 'Neutral'
      },
      { 
      question: '15.Lowry Bronsted defines acid as  ',
      options: [' A proton acceptor', ' An electron acceptor', 'A proton donor', 'An electron donor '],
      answer: 'A proton donor'
      },
      { 
      question: '16. Energy can neither be created nor destroyed but can be converted from one form to other is inferred from. ',
      options: ['zeroth law of thermodynamic ', 'first law of thermodynamic', 'second law of thermodynamic '],
      answer: 'first law of thermodynamic'
      },
      { 
      question: '17. Which of the statements defines the activity of a substance.  ',
      options: ['degree of randomness of a system ', 'a measure of its effective concentration under specified conditions', 'a measure of heat content of a substance. '],
      answer: 'a measure of its effective concentration under specified conditions'
      },
      { 
      question: '18. A system in which reactants and products are found in two or more phases is a. ',
      options: ['Phase equilibrium ', 'Chemical equilibrium ', 'Heterogeneous equilibrium'],
      answer: 'Heterogeneous equilibrium'
      },
      { 
      question: '19. Which of the following statements is true for the effect of catalyst on equilibrium.   ',
      options: ['affects the rates of the reactions', ' alter the equilibrium position', 'Catalyst remains in the reactants '],
      answer: 'affects the rates of the reactions'
      },
      { 
      question: '20. What happens when a catalyst is added to a system at equilibrium?    ',
      options: ['The reaction follows an alternative pathway of lower activation energy.', ' The heat of reaction decreases. ', 'The potential energy of the reactants decreases. '],
      answer: 'The reaction follows an alternative pathway of lower activation energy.'
      }
      ,
      // { 
      // question: ' The following factors affects the position of an equilibrium EXCEPT.    ',
      // options: ['Temperature ', ' Pressure', 'Catalyst'],
      // answer: 'Catalyst'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Which one of the following statements regarding energy is false?   ',
      // options: [' The total energy in a chemical universe (a system and its surroundings) is constant ', 'Energy can be converted from one form to another ', 'The energy stored in chemical bonds is referred to as kinetic energy. '],
      // answer: 'The energy stored in chemical bonds is referred to as kinetic energy.'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Which one of the following statements best describes the enthalpy change of a reaction?    ',
      // options: ['The energy released when chemical bonds are formed during a chemical reaction ', ' The energy consumed when chemical bonds are broken during a chemical reaction ', ' The difference between the energy released by bond formation and the energy consumed by bond cleavage during a chemical reaction '],
      // answer: 'The difference between the energy released by bond formation and the energy consumed by bond cleavage during a chemical reaction'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  Enthalpy is represented by which of the following symbols? ',
      // options: ['H', ' K', 'S ', 'B '],
      // answer: 'H'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: 'Which of the following statements regarding the Gibbs free energy change for a reaction is false?   ',
      // options: ['The Gibbs free energy change is the proportion of the enthalpy change of a reaction that is used to increase the entropy.', ': If the Gibbs free energy change for a reaction is negative, the reaction happens spontaneously. ', ' The Gibbs free energy is represented by the symbol G '],
      // answer: 'The Gibbs free energy change is the proportion of the enthalpy change of a reaction that is used to increase the entropy.'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  Energy is measured in which of the following units?   ',
      // options: [' Kelvin', 'Joule', 'Pascal ', 'Watt '],
      // answer: 'Joule'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '    The formation of a chemical bond releases energy. True or false?     ',
      // options: ['True', ' False', 'All of the above ', ' None of the above'],
      // answer: 'True'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: 'In case of spontaneous reaction, the reaction process favoured is.  ',
      // options: ['Forward', ' Both direction', 'Reverse ', ' No direction'],
      // answer: 'Forward'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Consider the following reaction in a galvanic cell  Zn+Cu2+ →Zn2+  Which if the following statements about the reaction is false? ',
      // options: ['The cell potential is positive ', ' The equilibrium constant is reater than one', 'Gibbs free energy is positive'],
      // answer: 'Gibb’s free energy is positive'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' What is the difference between S°, and ? S°, 298 for a chemical change? ',
      // options: ['S° standard enthalpy at 1 bar pressure ', ' ΔSo 298 Standard change in entropy at room temperature ', ' S° Entropy of a perfect crystal at absolute zero . '],
      // answer: 'ΔSo 298 Standard change in entropy at room temperature'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' ____ classifies acids and bases as specifies which accept and donates proton respectively. ',
      // options: [' Arrhenus Theory ', 'Bronsted-lowry Theory', 'Daltons Theory  ', ' Charles Darwin Theory  '],
      // answer: 'Bronsted-lowry Theory'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' The following are characteristics of gases except  ',
      // options: ['Definite shape', ' Indefinite shape', ' mobile ions ', ' loosely packed'],
      // answer: 'Definite shape'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' The measure of the hydrogen ion conc. (H+) is ____ ',
      // options: [' POH scale', ' H+ scale', 'PH scale', ' OH- scale'],
      // answer: 'PH scale'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' The rate law relates the rate of a chemical reaction to   ',
      // options: ['The concentration of a reaction', 'The temperature ', 'The activation energy ', ' The reaction mechanism'],
      // answer: 'The concentration of a reaction'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' As temperature decreases the reaction rate    ',
      // options: [' Decrease then increase', ' Decrease', 'Increases ', 'Stays the same '],
      // answer: 'increases'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  Which out of the following is not an intensive property   ',
      // options: [' Pressure ', ' Concentration', 'Density ', ' Volume'],
      // answer: 'Volume'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' The catalyzed reaction has a  ____ activation energy and thus causes  ____ reaction rate.   ',
      // options: ['Higher,Lower ', 'Higher, higher ', 'Lower,higher ', ' lower, steady'],
      // answer: 'Lower, higher'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  What is the phase change when solid changes to gas  ',
      // options: ['Melting ', 'Freezing ', 'Deposition ', 'Sublimation '],
      // answer: 'Sublimation'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Mole solute per kg of solutuion is   ',
      // options: [' Molarity', ' Concentration', 'Molality ', 'ion '],
      // answer: 'Molality'
      // }
      ]   
  };
  